Guide to the Ralph Hodgson Papers
Yale University Library
- Artwork, 1796-1951; Series III.; 1.0' (3 boxes)
  - ARTWORK BY HODGSON
    - Three small sketches in pen and ink of a man and a dog, and a sailing ship (Box 43, Folder 901)
      Inside envelope marked "Packington's Pound"
    - "Tomi San (Hanamaru)" pencil and crayon drawing, 1937 Jun 14
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1149
    - Two cards bearing pen and ink vignettes used in Silver Wedding and Other Poems, [1941] (Box 43, Folder 902)
    - Two men sitting on a sofa, with palms and a Hotel Corsica sign in background, drawing in pen and ink (Box 43, Folder 902a)
      Removed from J. H. Walsh, The Dogs of the British Islands, Being a Series of Articles on the Points of Their Various Breeds. 4th edition. London: Horace Cox, 1882
    - Woman walking away, drawing in pencil, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 903)
    - Woman's head, possibly Dorothy Hall Smith, three drawings in pencil, 1945, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1150
    - Photocopies of two cartoons in Fry's Magazine and Punch (Box 43, Folder 904)
    - Empty folders previously holding the above loose sketches, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1151
  - ARTWORK BY OTHERS
    - Baxter, W. G. Cartoons clipped from magazines, looseleaf and in an album, with ms. notes by Hodgson, 1884-88, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 64, folders 1134-1138
    - "The Bull Terrier Old New and its Origins" two folders containing clipped illustrations and prints to illustrate the history of the breed, 1837, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 64, folder 1139
      Includes an aquatint by Henry Alken
    - Cartoons by W. G. Baxter, F. A. Fraser, and others, clippings, ca. 1880-90 (Box 44, Folder 905-906)
    - Cook, Gordon. Two copperplate engravings of landscapes
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1152
    - Endo, Arata. Three sketches of Hodgson on one board, 1938 Jul 13 (Box 44, Folder 907)
    - Forain. Album of illustrations clipped from magazines, with miscellaneous clippings at back, 1926-51, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 908)
    - Gakuen, Jiyu. Sketch of Hodgson smoking a pipe. Isako, Senoo, ca. 1936 (Box 44, Folder 909)
    - H., W. E. "Great Island and Three Kings Island, New Zealand," pencil sketch, 1926 Aug 30 (Box 44, Folder 910)
    - Hummingbirds, colored cut-outs, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 911)
    - Kojima, Kikuo. Photocopy of a drawing of Hodgson, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 912)
    - Marbled endpapers removed from books (Box 44, Folder 913)
    - Russell, George William. Self portrait in colored pencil, signed AE, [1912 Sep] (Box 44, Folder 914)
    - Rutherston, Albert
      - Drawing of a female nude. Proof in color, 1923 Sep 1 (Box 44, Folder 915)
        Caption reads: "Proof No. 3 of 6 special proofs for presentation hand coloured by Albert R. for Ralph Hodgson"
      - Five designs for Cymbeline. Proofs in color, 1923
        See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1153
    - Scattergood-Kirkham, E. "Family Affairs," etching, 1937 Jan (Box 44, Folder 916)
    - Unidentified. Drawing of a blue bird accompanied by writing in Japanese, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 917)
    - Unidentified. Japanese woodblock print, hand colored
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1154
    - Unidentified. Oil painting, on board, of a brown spaniel, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 918)
    - Unidentified. "The Strange Adventures of a Dog-Cart," disbound, illustrated short story
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1155
    - Williams, Caroline. "The Towpath," etching, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1156
    - Yoshioka, Kenji. Watercolor of three birds, 1951 (Box 44, Folder 918a)
      Accompanied by address label with return address of Keiko Hani
    - Miscellaneous pen and ink sketches (Box 44, Folder 919)
    - Miscellaneous engravings, lithographs, woodcuts, clippings and photoreproductions, 1796-1935 (Box 44, Folder 920-926)
      See also: Oversize, box 65, folders 1157-1158
    - Miscellaneous engravings, lithographs, woodcuts, clippings and photoreproductions, 1796-1935 (Box 45, Folder 927-930)
    - Valentines, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 931)
- Printed Material, [1695-1975]; Series IV.; 3.4' (13 boxes)
  Series IV, Printed Material, is organized into four subseries: Pamphlets, Maps, Clippings, and Other Printed Material. Pamphlets and Maps are arranged alphabetically by author or title, if the author is unknown.
  - PAMPHLETS
    - Adelman, Seymour. "Equipping the Lewis and Clark Expedition." Reprinted from the Library Bulletin of the American Philosophical Society, [1945] (Box 46, Folder 932)
    - Bacon, Leonard
      - "Autumn Afternoon" printed Christmas token, 1951
        See: Box 2, folder 22
      - "Last of the Romans" printed Christmas token, 1947
        See: Box 1, folder 19
      - "Luis de Camoens" printed Christmas token, 1950
        See: Box 2, folder 21
      - "An Ode for the Two Hundred and Fiftieth Anniversary of the Founding of Yale College", 1951
    - Bacon, Martha. "The Unicorn" printed Christmas token, 1949
      See: Box 1, folder 20
    - Benét, William Rose
      - "Address to Archeus" printed Christmas token, 1949
        See: Box 3, folder 55
      - "The Star" printed Christmas token, 1947
    - Blakeney, Edward Henry
      - "O gorgeous remnants of departed summer..." printed Christmas token, 1932
        See: Box 4, folder 66
      - "The Falling Leaf" printed poem, n.d.
      - "To a Favourite Cat" printed poem, signed in manuscript, n.d.
      - "To the Memory of Dear 'Mr. Puff'" printed poem, n.d.
    - Coppard, A. E. "A Carol." With decorations by C. Lovat Fraser. Printed, not published for the friends of Earl and Florence Fisk. Printed Christmas token, 1947 Christmas
      See: Box 10, folder 195
    - Dalmon, Charles
      - "The Jolly Tinker" holograph poem, [1932]
    - Drinkwater, John
      - Brampton Broadsheets No. 1 "Penelope's Trees" inscribed to Hodgson, 1930 Jan (Box 46, Folder 933)
      - Rhyme Sheet: [Second Series] No. 12 "For a Guest Room" signed by John Drinkwater (Box 46, Folder 934)
    - Farano, Michel
      - "A Barn in Bethlehem" printed Christmas token, inscribed to Hodgson, signed by Farano, [1959]
        See: Box 9, folder 183
      - "The Peaceable Kingdom" printed Christmas token, n.d.
        See: Box 9, folder 184
    - Hodgson, Ralph. "Ralph Hodgson. Time, You Old Gypsy Man," printed Christmas token from Reinold and Hannie Kuipers-Verwey, 1950 (Box 46, Folder 935)
    - Jackson, Holbrook. "The Dictatorship of the Lay-Out Man." Reprinted from Typography 7, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 936)
    - Levine, Isaac. The Song-Adventures of Isaac Levine. Chicago: The Paragon Press, 1950 (Box 46, Folder 937)
      Accompanied by The Queen of Elfland's Daughter (a Moon Fantasy) 1951
    - Moore, John Travers. Near Centerville. Cincinnati: Moore, [1950] (Box 46, Folder 938)
    - Oakley, Ruth
      - "Blue Spruce," poem inscribed and signed, 1960
      - "Edwina Mountbatten," poem inscribed and signed, 1960
    - O'Sullivan, Seumas. Verses Sacred and Profane. Dublin: Maunsel Co., Ltd., 1908 (Box 46, Folder 939)
      Tipped onto preliminary leaf is a poem, "Dawn in the City" by (or after?) George Stuart
    - The Poetical Birthday Book; or, Characters from the Poets. Edited by the Countess of Portsmouth. London: Hatchards, 1879 (Box 46, Folder 940)
      Used as an autograph album; notable signatures include those of I. J. Paderewski, Arthur James Balfour, George Wyndham, and Charles Hubert Hastings Parry
    - Rothenstein, William. Portrait Drawings and Dry-Points London: The Cotswold Gallery, 1922 Jan (Box 46, Folder 941)
    - The Royal Engagement Pocket Atlas for the Year MDCCXCIX, [1799] (Box 46, Folder 942)
      Inscribed by Sarah Morris Febry. 16, 1799, and stamped on cover Miss Sh. Morris 1799. Accompanied by six little cards with woodcuts and verses on them
    - Royal Society of Literature, Academic Committee. Addresses of Reception to Mrs. Alice Meynell...Award of the Edmond de Polignac Prize to Ralph Hodgson by J. Masefield London: Humphrey Milford, 1915
      See: Box 13, folder 262
    - Saul, George Brandon. October Sheaf. Iowa City: The Prairie Press, 1951 (Box 46, Folder 943)
    - Schroeder, Ralph L. "Ralph Hodgson: 1871-1962," The Courier Syracuse University Library Associates, 1963 Sep
      See: Box 16, folder 336
    - Sibson, T. Sketches of Expeditions, from the Pickwick Club London, [1885] (Box 46, Folder 944)
    - Smart, Christopher. A Song to David. [Oxford: Clarendon Press], [1926] (Box 46, Folder 945)
      Tipped onto preliminary leaf is a poem by Edmund Blunden, "on receiving from the Clarendon Press the new Facsimile edition of Christopher Smart's "Song to David," 1763
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets and broadsides of poetry, [1905]-60 (Box 46, Folder 946-947)
    - Other miscellaneous pamphlets and newsletters, 1893-1958 (Box 46, Folder 948-949)
    - Illustrators and Caricaturists - a collection of pamphlets, book chapters, and clippings, bound together, ca. 1830-90 (Box 47, Folder 950)
    - Londoniana. A collection of pamphlets, book chapters and clippings bound together, ca. 1830-90 (Box 48, Folder 951)
    - Poetical Criticism -- a collection of pamphlets, book chapters, and clippings bound together, ca. 1830-90 (Box 49, Folder 952)
    - Poetical Criticism -- a collection of pamphlets, book chapters, and clippings bound together, ca. 1830-90 (Box 50, Folder 953)
    - Poetical Criticism -- a collection of pamphlets, book chapters, and clippings bound together, ca. 1830-90 (Box 51, Folder 954)
    - Cullings from Scrutiny, 1932-38 (Box 52, Folder 955)
  - MAPS
    - Baines, Edward. History, Directory and Gazetteer of Lancashire. 12 maps, 2 tables, 1824 (Box 53, Folder 956)
    - Bartholomew's Revised 'Half-Inch' Contoured Maps. England Sheet 4. Teesdale. Edinburgh: John Bartholomew Son, Ltd. (Box 53, Folder 957)
    - Betts's New Itinerant and Commercial Map of England and Wales. London: John Betts, 1840 (Box 53, Folder 958)
    - Cheffins's Map of the English Scotch Railways. Fourth edition. London: Charles F. Cheffins (Box 53, Folder 959)
    - Durham London: Kelly Co. Post Office Directory Offices, 1879
      See: Oversize, Box 65, folder 1159
      Lacking right border
    - France in Departments [London]: G.F. Cruchley (Box 53, Folder 960)
    - Frogett's Map of the Country Fifteen Miles Round London. [London]: G.F. Cruchley (Box 53, Folder 961)
    - Hampshire and Berkshire. Sheet no. 19. London: Published by G. J. Cary, 1823 June (Box 53, Folder 962)
    - The Ichnography of the Cities of London and Westminster and the Borough of Southwark [London]: Engraved for the General Magazine of Arts Sciences for W. Owen at Temple Bar, 1757
      See: Oversize, Box 65, folder 1160
    - Italy [London]: G.F. Cruchley (Box 53, Folder 963)
    - Japan. Map of Imperial Government Railways Tokyo, Japan: Traffic Department, Imperial Government Railways, 1913 Mar (Box 53, Folder 964)
    - Letts's Bicycle and Tourist Maps of England and Wales, 1883 (Box 53, Folder 965)
    - Map of the County Palatine of Durham. London: C. I. Greenwood, 1831 (Box 54, Folder 966)
    - Maps of London, 1833-1953, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 967)
      See also: Oversize, Box 65, folders 1161-1162
      Reproductions of old maps of London
    - Morden, Robt. Episcopatus Dunelmensis Vulgo. The Bishoprick of Durham., [1695]
      See: Oversize, box 67, folder 1190
      With note in Hodgson's hand at bottom "From Camden's Britannia 1695"
    - National Geographic Society maps, 1918-53 (Box 54, Folder 968-971)
    - New 1 Inch Ordnance Survey, England and Wales. Sheet 123. London: Edward Stanford (Box 54, Folder 972)
    - Northumberland. London: Kelly Co. Post Office Directory Offices, 1879
      See: Oversize, Box 65, folder 1163
    - Northumberland. Sheet no. 53. London: Published by G. J. Cary, 1825 Oct (Box 54, Folder 973)
    - Northumberland. Sheet no. 58. London: Published by G. J. Cary, 1827 Feb (Box 54, Folder 974)
    - Ordnance Survey. Basingstoke. No. 12. London: Sold by Js. Wyld Son, 1817 Aug (Box 54, Folder 975)
    - Ordnance Survey. One-Inch Map of Great Britain. Durham. Sheet no. 85., 1955 (Box 54, Folder 976)
    - Ordnance Survey of Scotland. Aberdeen and Banff Sheet 15. Southampton: Ordnance Survey Office, 1912 (Box 54, Folder 977)
    - Ordnance Survey of Scotland. Dornoch and Cromarty Sheet 9. Southampton: Ordnance Survey Office, 1913 (Box 54, Folder 978)
    - Ordnance Survey of Scotland. Dundee, Perth and Stirling. Sheet 23. Southampton: Ordnance Survey Office, 1913 (Box 55, Folder 979)
    - Philips' Authentic Imperial Maps for Tourists Travellers. China London: George Philip Son, Ltd. (Box 55, Folder 980)
    - Scotland. London: Published by Richd. Holmes Laurie, 1828 Feb (Box 55, Folder 981)
    - Slip case for a folding missing map, London Environs (Ordnance Skeleton Survey) London: Edward Stanford (Box 55, Folder 982)
  - CLIPPINGS
    - Re: Ralph Hodgson
      - Hodgson interviews, 1939-61, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 983)
        See also: Oversize, box 65, folder 1163a
      - Tributes to Hodgson, 1961-68, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 984)
    - Re: Animals
      - Birds, loose clippings and in notebooks, 1838-1960, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 985-989)
      - Birds, notebook, 1908-60, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 990)
      - Dogs, 1873-1957, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 991-993)
      - Other animals, 1938-[60], n.d. (Box 57, Folder 994)
    - Re: Other
      - Art (Box 57, Folder 995-997)
      - Authors, [1876-1970], n.d. (Box 57, Folder 998-1000)
      - Bibliography, [1899-1969], n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1001)
      - Book reviews, 1928-[74], n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1002-1005)
      - English antiquities, [1900]-73, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1006-1007)
      - Poetry, 1887-1972, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1008)
      - Miscellaneous, 1915-[75], n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1009-1015)
        See also: Oversize, box 65, folders 1164-1165
      - Miscellaneous, 1915-[75], n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1016-1017)
  - OTHER PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Business and calling cards (Box 58, Folder 1018)
    - Christmas and New Year's greeting with drawing of a dog by Hodgson (Box 58, Folder 1019)
    - "Copies of Old Sign Boards at The Old Curiosity Shop, Falmouth" broadside, n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1165a
    - Genealogy of the Bagnolds, including Enid Bagnold, 1927 Nov (Box 58, Folder 1020)
    - Keats, John. The Poetical Works of John Keats. A New Edition. London: Edward Moxon, 1850 (Box 58, Folder 1020a)
      With ms. annotations
    - King Edward VIII stamps (23 on envelopes, cancelled), 1936-37 (Box 58, Folder 1021)
    - "The Life and Death of Richard Titheridge Commonly Known in Alresford, Winchester, and Southampton as Dickey Dung Prong...." broadside (Box 58, Folder 1022)
      See: Box bsd, folder 1211a
    - Miscellaneous pages from magazines and books used for "Without Comment", 1820-99 (Box 58, Folder 1023)
    - Pages from the New English Weekly, 1933-36 (Box 58, Folder 1023a)
    - Pages from booksellers' catalogs, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1024)
    - Photographic prints of London (Box 58, Folder 1025)
    - Program of American Conservatory of Music Recital featuring the song, "Time, you old gypsy man", 1936 (Box 58, Folder 1026)
    - Program of Choral Festival at Minerva High School featuring musical setting of "The Hammers" by Gerhard Track, [1968] (Box 58, Folder 1027)
    - Miscellaneous pages from English tradesmen directories and advertisements, 1886-94, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1028)
    - "With compliments from the author" cards from books in Hodgson's library, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1029)
    - Miscellaneous printed items, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1030-1031)
- Photographs, 1930-[1950]; Series V.; 0.4' (1 box)
  Series V, Photographs, is organized into three subseries: People, Dogs, and Buildings.
  - PEOPLE
    - Hodgson and others in Japan, 1938, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1032)
    - The Shibuyas and Saitos, 1930-31 (Box 59, Folder 1033)
    - Unidentified people in Japan, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1034-1035)
    - Ralph Hodgson and Siegfried Sassoon
      See: Box 60, folder 1102
    - The Adelmans, [1950 Aug 20] (Box 59, Folder 1036)
    - Miss Adelaide Detchon, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1037)
    - "Mid 19th Century Photographs of Scottish Society", n.d.
      See: Oversize, box 65a?, folder 1167a
    - Other unidentified people, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1038)
  - DOGS
    See also: Box 1, folder 6
    - "Towzer. An Akita Dog" photograph album, with photographs only on the first page, of the dog as a puppy, [1936] (Box 59, Folder 1039)
    - Monthly photographs of Towzer, from puppy to dog, [1935], n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1040-1042)
    - Copy prints from nitrate negatives of Towzer, [1935] (Box 59, Folder 1043)
    - Unidentified dogs, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1044)
    - Japanese postcards of dogs and artwork depicting dogs (Box 59, Folder 1045)
  - BUILDINGS
    - Historical buildings in England (Box 59, Folder 1046)
    - Postcards of buildings, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1047)
- Siegfried Sassoon Collection, 1889-1952; Series VI.; 1.4' (3 boxes)
  Series VI, Siegfried Sassoon Collection, is organized into five subseries: Writings, Photographs, Artwork, Printed Material, and Other Papers. The Writings are organized into Articles, Novels, and Poetry, which are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - WRITINGS
    - Articles
      - "Beddoes: A Personal Approach" The Listener, 1935 Dec 24 (Box 60, Folder 1048)
      - "Footnotes on the Last Fifty Years" The Saturday Book Sixth Year, galleys, corrected in an unidentified hand, 1946 Jun 6
        See: Oversize, bsd, folder 1212
      - "What Hope for Poetry?" Harper's Bazaar, [1935 Dec]
        See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1166
    - Novels
      Memoirs of a Fox-Hunting Man
      - Chapter IX, In the Army, typescript draft, corrected, n.d.
      - Chapter X, At the Front, typescript draft, corrected, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1050)
      - Part one, galleys, corrected, [1928?]
        See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1193
      - Part two, galleys, corrected, 1928 Jun
        See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1194
      - Part three, galleys, corrected, 1928 Jun
        See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1195
      - Parts four and five, galleys, corrected, 1928 Jun
        See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1196
      - Parts six and seven, galleys, corrected, 1928 Jun
        See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1197
      - Parts eight and nine, galleys, corrected, 1928 Jun
        See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1198
      - Part ten, galleys, corrected, 1928 Jun
        See: Oversize, box 68a, folder 1199
      - Page proof, corrected, of pages 1-288, 1928 (Box 60, Folder 1051)
      - Reviews: clippings, 1928-29 (Box 60, Folder 1052)
      - Memoirs of an Infantry Officer
        - Excerpts printed in the Daily Telegraph: parts XIV-XVIII (end), [1930 Aug] (Box 60, Folder 1053)
      - Meredith
        - Chapters 1-3, galleys, corrected, [1947]
          See: Oversize, box 68b, folder 1200
        - Chapters 4-10, galleys, corrected, [1947]
          See: Oversize, box 68b, folder 1201
        - Chapters 11-14, galleys, corrected, [1948?]
          See: Oversize, box 68b, folder 1202
        - Chapters 15-20, galleys, corrected, [1948?]
          See: Oversize, box 68b, folder 1203
      - The Old Century
        - Chapter VI of Book II, "And Seven More Years," galleys, corrected, ca. 1938
          See: Oversize, box 68c, folder 1204
        - Proof copy in yellow wrappers, corrected, inscribed by Sassoon to Hodgson, with watercolor self-portrait on the title page, ca. 1938 (Box 60, Folder 1054)
      - Sherston's Progress
        - Page proofs of the limited, signed edition, corrected by Sassoon and Max Beerbohm, 1936 (Box 60, Folder 1055)
      - Siegfried's Journey, 1916-1920
        - Chapter IX, page proof, corrected, [1945?] (Box 60, Folder 1056)
        - Chapter XV, page proof, corrected, [1945?] (Box 60, Folder 1057)
      - The Weald of Youth
        - Chapters 1-2, galleys, corrected, 1941 Oct 17
          See: Oversize, box 68d, folder 1205
        - Chapters 3-6, galleys, corrected, [1941?]
          See: Oversize, box 68d, folder 1206
        - Chapters 7-9, galleys, corrected, [1942?]
          See: Oversize, box 68d, folder 1207
        - Chapters 10-12, galleys, corrected, 1942 Mar 31
          See: Oversize, box 68d, folder 1208
        - Chapters 13-17, galleys, corrected, [1942]
          See: Oversize, box 68d, folder 1209
        - Specimen proof, 1942 (Box 60, Folder 1058)
    - Poetry
      - "Again the Dead..." holograph, n.d.
        See: "They Were Not True", Box 60, folder 1084
      - "An Asking" proof, 1950 Mar 15 (Box 60, Folder 1059)
        With "At Max Gate" at bottom
      - "At Max Gate" proof, corrected, 1950 Mar 15
        See: "An Asking", Box 60 folder 1059
      - "Babylon," holograph, 1932 Oct 8 (Box 60, Folder 1060)
      - "Childhood," holograph, 1929 Apr 8
        See: Vigils, Box 61 folder 1089
        Working title: "Childhood Recovered"
      - Collected Poems specimen proof, 1946 (Box 60, Folder 1061)
      - "Confederacy with Oblivion," holograph, 1948 Jan 18
        See: Box 24, folder 485
      - "Credo," holograph, 1932 Jun 21
        See: Vigils, Box 61, folder 1089
        Working title: "Credo: 1932"
      - "December Stillness," holograph, 1930 Dec 24
      - "Earth and Heaven," holograph, 1936 Dec 5 (Box 60, Folder 1062)
      - "Elected Silence," holograph, 1932 Dec 16 (Box 60, Folder 1063)
        Working title: "[Where Voices Vanish into Dream...]"
      - "An Emblem," holograph, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1064)
        With "Long Ago" and "Vibrations" at bottom
      - "An Escapist," holograph, n.d.
        See: "Lack of Foresight", Box 60 folder 1089
      - "Everyone Sang," holograph, n.d.
        See: Vigils, Box 60, folder 1089
      - "Farewell to Youth," holograph, 1929 Mar
      - "A Glimpse of Fitz," holograph, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 1065)
      - "Heytesbury House, Wiltshire Overhears The Muse and Mastiff, 1938 Aug 15 (Box 60, Folder 1066)
      - "A Hint," proof, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1067)
      - "[In me, past, present, future meet...]" holograph, n.d.
        Also published with the title "Apocalypse"
      - "Innovations," holograph, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 1068)
        With "Old-Fashioned Weather" on verso
      - "Lack of Foresight," holograph, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 1069)
        With "An Escapist" on verso
      - "LINES: Addressed to the Lord Rector of the University of Manchester," holograph, 1923 Nov 7 (Box 60, Folder 1070)
        With one line of poetry on a scrap of paper: "Poor Poetry's evening wasted! But I feel better for the expectoration," signed by Sassoon
      - "Lines Written in the Reform Club" Broadsheet, printed by Philip Sainsbury, at the FAVIL Press, 1921 (Box 60, Folder 1071)
      - "Litany of the Lost," proof, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1072)
      - "Long Ago," holograph, n.d.
        See: "An Emblem", Box 60, folder 1064
      - "Midsummer Eve," holograph, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1073)
        Working title: "A Message for Time"
      - "[The mind of man, environing its thought...]," holograph, 1932 Sep 11
        See: "[The multitudinous dead, like books unread...]", Box 60, folder 1074
      - "[The multitudinous dead, like books unread...]," holograph, 1932 Aug 7 (Box 60, Folder 1074)
        With "[The mind of man, environing its thought...]" at bottom of page
      - "Multum in Parvo," holograph, 1933 Jan 13 (Box 60, Folder 1075)
      - "My Reminiscences," holograph, 1924 Jan 19 (Box 60, Folder 1076)
      - "Nativity," holograph, n.d.
      - "A 1940 Memory," proof, 1943 Jul (Box 60, Folder 1077)
      - "1935," holograph, 1932 Oct 29 (Box 60, Folder 1078)
        With note at top to Hodgson
      - "November Dusk," holograph, 1932 Nov 22 (Box 60, Folder 1079)
      - "Old-Fashioned Weather"
        See: "Innovations", Box 60, folder 1068
        Working title: "Traditional Weather"